<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How I&#39;ve got into this ... Baking on A personal AB²C² weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How I&#39;ve got into this ... Baking on A personal AB²C² weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 09:27:43 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.jkl52.be/baking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Baker&#39;s log</title>
      <link>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 07:22:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/log/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;m not in the mood to post everything in detail each time I bake, maybe I can try to keep a baker&amp;rsquo;s log. A small table just enumerating what i did.
Logs dateweightflourhydrationsalt iconJuly 19th 2020800gr.25/75 rye/white80%2.25% Slightly different rising times due to bad planning. Preferment: 24h (vs 12h). First rise: 30+45+45 (vs 30+45+45+30). Second rise: 18h (vs 12h).For the first time I shared my bread with the neighbours. Blame Ken&#39;s Duvel from yesterday !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The recipe is settling</title>
      <link>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200509/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 08:52:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200509/</guid>
      <description>The recipe is settling With the experiments of the lasts week(s), I&amp;rsquo;m tuning the recipe. Currently the one that I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with is:
The preferment  20 grams of rye flour 100 grams of other flour 120 grams of water 24 grams of starter   The complete build  116 grams of rye flour 564 grams of other flour 520 grams of water 18 grams of salt    There are still plenty of parameters to toy around with, but at least I have some base to start from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Corona weekend coming up</title>
      <link>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200507/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 15:24:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200507/</guid>
      <description>Another Corona weekend coming up As the family is still in/around the house, I&amp;rsquo;ll not start brewing. Let&amp;rsquo;s bake another bread. Last week, we bought bread from a general grocery shop. I must say, &amp;hellip; there is a difference !!
Day -1, 15h15 - Waking up the starter I&amp;rsquo;ve binned half of the starter and re-fed it with 50/50 water/flour.
Day 0, 06h45 - Preferment As the Corona crisis is still in full force, (general) flour isn&amp;rsquo;t easy to get your hands on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Any Irish ?</title>
      <link>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200502/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 10:26:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200502/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s try out this Irish recipe I&amp;rsquo;ve been browsing the Internet in search for how to get started with sourdough. One Youtube channel I found is &amp;ldquo;ilovecookingireland&amp;rdquo;. Patrick Ryan gives a masterclass on how to simply bake 2 loaves with sourdough.
  This recipe is different from what I have tried before: there is not preferment. Ah no guts, no glory &amp;hellip; We&amp;rsquo;ll give it a try.
Mise en place  400 grams of white flour 230 grams of water 5 grams of salt 160 grams of starter    Mise en place   Recipe Mixing and first proofing Everthing, except for the start, went into the bows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a daily bread recipe</title>
      <link>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200430/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 07:05:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200430/</guid>
      <description>Towards a daily bread recipe So, despite all the mistakes, the bread ended up quite nice and tasty. Even my daughter likes it, how great is that :) As it was quite a large bread, it lasted a couple of days. I had to pack it with plastic though. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna try again and try to find a recipe that will be my default, my daily bread recipe.
1. Wake-up starter (day -1 @ 18h50) Got the starter out of the fridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second attempt</title>
      <link>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200425/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 07:00:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200425/</guid>
      <description>All right, the first attempt was a failure. That&amp;rsquo;s no big deal, is it ? After giving it some thought, I concluded the following:
 don&amp;rsquo;t feed the starter right before using it 12h in the fridge is no good option for fermenting  So &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s one week later &amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s try again.
07h00: Revive the starter I got the starter from the fridge and fed it. Throwing half of the starter away, replace that same weight with 50/50 water and all-purpose flour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s start with a starter</title>
      <link>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200404/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 09:36:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>&lt;i&gt;fname&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt;lname&lt;/i&gt;A T&lt;i&gt;gmail.com&lt;/i&gt; (Jo Vliegen)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jkl52.be/baking/200404/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a starter Saturday, April 4th 2020 This is written during the Corona crisis. Probably I should add a wikipedia link later (as if that&amp;rsquo;s going to happen). Because we have to stay home #blijfinuwkot I thought it was a good idea to make a sourdough starter.
With some browsing on the Internet and my personal advisor I got started.
  A starting starter - day 0   After a call with my personal coach he pointed out that &amp;ldquo;00&amp;rdquo; (doppio zero) flour might not be ideal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>